Register of the Bertram David Wolfe papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1914-1976 (Boxes 16-54)
  - "French Socialism, German Theory, and the Flaw in the Foundation of the Socialist International," in John Sheldon Curtiss, ed., Essays in Russian and Soviet History in Honor of Geroid Tanqueray Robinson, 1963 (Folder 44: 3)
    Galley proofs and printed copy.
  - Review in New York Times of Victor Serge, Memoirs of a Revolutionary, 1901-1941, 1963; Printed copy (Folder 44: 4)
  - "Lenin and Inessa Armand," Slavic Review, 1963 March (Folder 44: 5)
    Typescript, printed copy, clipping, and Spanish translation.
  - "War Comes to Russia," Russian Review, 1963 April; Printed copy, offprints, and photocopy (Folder 44: 6)
  - Review in New York Times of Isaac Deutscher, The Prophet Outcast: Trotsky, 1929-1940, and Irving Howe, ed., The Basic Writings of Trotsky, 1963 November 3; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 44: 7)
  - Introduction to Angelica Balabanoff, Impressions of Lenin, 1964 (Folder 44: 8)
  - Speech on communism in the Soviet Union, 1964?; Typescript (Folder 44: 9)
  - Review in New York Herald-Tribune of Louis Fischer, The Life of Lenin: A Biography, Robert Payne, The Life and Death of Lenin, and Stefan T. Possony, Lenin: The Compulsive Revolutionary, 1964 June 14; Printed copy (Folder 44: 10)
  - "Leninism," speech, Conference on One Hundred Years of Revolutionary Internationals, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford University, 1964 October (Folder 44: 11)
    Mimeograph, printed copy, and reviews.
  - "Titans Locked in Combat," two-part article, Russian Review, 1964 October and 1965 January (Folder 44: 12)
    Typescript, printed copy, offprints, and correspondence.
  - Marxism: One Hundred Years in the Life of a Doctrine (1965)
    - General (Folder 45: 1)
      Memorandum and corrections (typewritten), French translation of excerpts (printed copy), and miscellaneous printed matter.
    - Reviews
      - English, Printed copies (Folder 45: 2)
      - French, Printed copies (Folder 45: 3)
      - German (Folder 45: 4)
        Mimeographed and printed copies, and typed translations.
      - Russian (Folder 45: 5)
        Printed copies and typed translations.
    - Translation, Spanish, Printed copy (Folder 45: 6)
  - Strange Communists I Have Known (1965)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Folder 45: 7)
    - Drafts (Folder 45: 8)
      Typescripts. Introduction and Chapter II, "The Catholic Communist."
    - Reviews, Printed and typed copies (Folder 45: 9)
    - Translation, Japanese, Printed copy (Folder 45: 10)
  - Review in New York Times of E. H. Carr, A History of Soviet Russia, Vol. VII, 1965 February 7; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 45: 11)
  - Report on manuscript by George Katkov, 1965 May 6; Typescript (Folder 45: 12)
  - Review in Problems of Communism of Louis Aragon, A History of the USSR from Lenin to Khrushchev, 1965 July-August; Printed copy (Folder 45: 13)
  - Review in Book Week of Robert C. Tucker and Stephen F. Cohen, ed., The Great Purge Trial, 1965 July 4; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 45: 14)
  - Review in Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science of Francis B. Randall, Stalin's Russia: An Historical Reconsideration, 1966 (Folder 45: 15)
  - "V. I. Lenin and Maxim Gorky: A Study of a Stormy Friendship,", 1966; Typescript (Folder 45: 16)
  - Introduction to Aleksandr Kerenskii, speech, Stanford University, 1966 February 1; Typescript (Folder 45: 17)
  - "Some Reflections on the Convergence Theory," Western Politica, 1966 Autumn; Typescript, printed copy and clipping (Folder 45: 18)
  - Letter to the editor, Russian Review, 1966? October 4; Typescript (Folder 45: 19)
  - Review in Slavic Review of Z. A. B. Zeman and W. B. Scharlau, The Merchant of Revolution: The Life of Alexander Israel Helphand (Parvus), 1867-1924, 1966 December (Folder 45: 20)
    Typescript, galley proofs, and correspondence.
  - " Das Kapital One Hundred Years Later," Antioch Review, 1966-1967 Winter (Folder 46: 1-2)
    Mimeograph, printed copy, abstract (typewritten), correspondence, and Japanese, Korean, Spanish and Vietnamese translations (1967-1968).
  - The Bridge and the Abyss: The Troubled Friendship of Maxim Gorky and V.I. Lenin (1967)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Folder 46: 3)
    - Drafts, Typescripts
      - Bound volume (Folder 46: 4)
      - Preliminary leaves (Folder 46: 5)
      - Foreword (Folder 46: 6)
      - "The Poet and the Politician" (Folder 46: 7)
      - "Out of the Depths" (Folder 46: 8)
      - "Wander Years" (Folder 46: 9)
      - "Liberty, Classes, Man and God" (Folder 46: 10)
      - "Of Truth and the Lie" (Folder 46: 11)
      - "The Poison of Power" (Folder 47: 1)
      - "Curator of Russian Culture, I: The Great Entrepreneur" (Folder 47: 2)
      - "Curator of Russian Culture, II: Justice for Grand Dukes and Writers" (Folder 47: 3)
      - "Curator of Russian Culture, III: The Death of Two Poets" (Folder 47: 4)
      - "The End of a Friendship" (Folder 47: 5)
      - "Epilogue: Gorky's Three Portraits of Lenin" (Folder 47: 6)
      - Postscript, "The Two Deaths of Maxim Gorky" (Folder 47: 7)
      - Selected bibliography (Folder 47: 8)
    - Reviews
      - English, Printed copies (Folder 47: 9)
      - German, Typed, mimeographed and printed copies (Folder 47: 10)
      - Russian (Folder 47: 11)
    - Translation, German (Folder 47: 12)
      Typescript. Foreword by Karl Kautsky, Jr.
  - Introduction to Lev Trotskii, Stalin: An Appraisal of The Man and His Influence (1967)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Folder 47: 13)
    - Typescript (Folder 47: 14)
  - "Lenin, the Architect of Twentieth-Century Totalitrianism," in The Russian Revolution, 1967 (Folder 47: 15)
    Typescript, printed copy, and French translation.
  - "Reflections on the Future of the Soviet System," in Samuel Hendel and Randolph L. Braham, ed., The USSR After Fifty Years, 1967 (Folder 48: 1)
    Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence (1965-1967).
  - Report on manuscript by J.B. Sorenson, 1967; Typescript (Folder 48: 2)
  - "Rise and Fall of the First International," lecture, 1967; Typewritten notes (Folder 48: 3)
  - "Stalin, Joseph (1879-1953)," Groliers Encyclopedia, 1967; Printed copy (Folder 48: 4)
  - "The Transformations of Marxism-Leninism as an Ideology," speech, 1967? (Folder 48: 5)
    Typescript. Includes comments by George L. Kline.
  - Review in Spectator of George Katkov, Russia, 1917: The February Revolution, 1967 February 24 (Folder 48: 6)
  - "Reflections on the Future of the Soviet System," lecture, University of San Francisco, 1967 March 19; Typewritten notes (Folder 48: 7)
  - Letter to the editor (with Richard V. Allen, Milorad M. Drachkovitch, and Edward J. Rozek), Palo Alto Times, 1967 March 23; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 48: 8)
  - "Backwardness and Industrialization in Russian History and Thought," Slavic Review, 1967 June (Folder 48: 9)
    Typescript, printed copy, Italian translation (printed copy), and correspondence (1968).
  - Review in Chicago Daily News of Svetlana Allilueva, Twenty Letters to a Friend, 1967 September 23; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 48: 10)
  - Review in Chicago Daily News of George F. Kennan, Memoirs, 1925-1950, 1967 November 4; Typescript (Folder 48: 11)
  - Letter to the editor, Russian Review, 1967 November 7; Notes, typescript and printed copy (Folder 48: 12)
  - "Dictatorship's Lure for Lenin," Justice, 1967 December 1; Printed copy (Folder 48: 13)
  - "Marxism and the Russian Revolution," in Milorad M. Drachkovitch, ed., Fifty Years of Communism in Russia, 1968 (Folder 48: 14)
    Printed copy and reviews.
  - Review of Andre Malraux, Anti-Memoirs, 1968?; Typescript (Folder 48: 15)
  - "A Historian Looks at the Convergence Theory," in Paul Kurtz, ed., Sidney Hook and the Contemporary World, 1968 (Folder 48: 16)
    Typescript, printed copy, correspondence, comments by John H. Kautsky (typescript), comments by J. K. Galbraith, H. Gordon Skilling, Alfred G. Meyer and John H. Kautsky (printed copies), Humanist, (September-October 1968) and reply by Bertram D. Wolfe (typescript and printed copy), Humanist (November-December 1968).
  - Translation of Vladimir Maiakovskii, "To His Own Beloved Self, the Author Dedicates These Lines," Slavic Review, 1968 December; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 48: 17)
  - Translation of Boris Slutskii, "God," Slavic Review, 1968 December; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 48: 18)
  - "Chinese Cultural Revolution," lecture, 1969?; Typewritten notes (Folder 48: 19)
  - An Ideology in Power: Reflections on the Russian Revolution (1969)
    - General, 1968-1971 (Folder 48: 20)
      Printed copies. Correspondence, press releases, and fragments of text.
    - Reviews
      - General (Folder 48: 21)
        Typed and printed copies, with press releases.
      - Titarenko, S. L., Voprosy Istorii KPSS, 1972 (Folder 48: 22)
        Printed copy (in Russian), with typed translation.
  - Introduction to Nikolai Valentinov, The Early Years of Lenin, 1969 (Folder 49: 1)
    Typescript, printed copy, correspondence (1965-1969), French and Spanish translations (printed copies), and reviews.
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1969; Typewritten notes (Folder 49: 2)
  - "Notes on Party Life under Lenin,", 1969?; Typescript (Folder 49: 3)
  - Review of Walter Laqueur, The Fate of the Revolution, 1969; Typescript (Folder 49: 4)
  - Review of George Vernadsky, The Tsardom of Moscow, 1547-1682, 1969?; Typescript (Folder 49: 5)
  - Review in Russian Review of Maksim Gorkii, Untimely Thoughts: Essays on Revolution, Culture, and the Bolsheviks, 1917-1918, 1969 January; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 49: 6)
  - "Krupskaya Purges the People's Libraries," Survey, 1969 Summer (Folder 49: 7)
    Typescript, printed copy, correspondence, and research material (in Russian, with translations).
  - Review in Slavic Review of Robert Conquest, The Great Terror, 1969 June (Folder 49: 8)
    Typescript, correspondence, and letter to the editor (typescript, galley proofs and printed copy), Slavic Review.
  - "The Rehabilitation of an Unwriter: A Fragment of an Autobiography," Russian Review, 1969 July; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 49: 9)
  - "Leon Felipe: Poet of Spain's Exodus and Tears," TriQuarterly, 1969 Fall (Folder 49: 10)
    Typescript, printed copy, correspondence, and Spanish translation.
  - Letter to the editor, Palo Alto Times, 1969 September 2; Printed copy (Folder 49: 11)
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1970s; Typewritten notes and printed matter (Folder 49: 12-14)
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, circa 1970; Typewritten notes and printed matter (Folder 50: 1-3)
  - "My Life in Two Centuries" (1970s)
    - Introduction by Leonard Schapiro, Typescript (Folder 50: 4)
    - Notes for last chapter (never written) (Folder 50: 5)
      Holograph, with printed matter.
  - Translation of Ivan Elagin, "All Rights Reserved," poem, 1970s; Typescript (Folder 50: 6)
  - Translation of Ivan Elagin, "Amnesty," poem, 1970s (Folder 50: 7)
    Typescript and galley proofs.
  - Untitled collection of essays, 1970s (Folder 50: 8)
    Introduction (typewritten) by P. P. Witonski.
  - Broadcast on V. I. Lenin, National Broadcasting Company, 1970; Typescript (Folder 50: 9)
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1970; Typewritten notes (Folder 50: 10-11)
  - "A Yankee in Mexico," speech, 1970; Typewritten notes (Folder 50: 12)
  - Review in Russia Review of Svetlana Allilueva, Only One Year, 1970 January; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 50: 13)
  - "Dress Rehearsals for the Great Terror," Studies in Comparative Communism (1970 April)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Folder 51: 1-2)
    - Text (Folder 51: 3)
      Typescript drafts, printed copy, offprint, and French translation.
  - Introduction to Lev Trotskii, Lenin: Notes for a Biographer (1971)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Folder 51: 4)
    - Reviews, Printed copies (Folder 51: 5)
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1971; Typewritten notes (Folder 51: 6)
  - Review in Slavic Review of Kenneth F. and Heloise P. Mailloux, Lenin: The Exile Returns, 1971? (Folder 51: 7)
  - Report on Robert H. McNeal, "Krupskaya: Bride of the Revolution,", 1971 April 16 (Folder 51: 8)
  - Broadcast on death of Nikita Khrushchev, Radio Liberty, 1971 September (Folder 51: 9)
  - Letter to the editor, Stanford Daily, 1971 December 3 (Folder 51: 10)
  - "The Government of Doctor Caligari," National Review, 1971 December 31 (Folder 51: 11)
    Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence (1971-1972).
  - "The Influence of Lenin on the History of Our Times: The Question of Totalitarianism," in Bernard W. Eissenstat, ed., Lenin and Leninism, 1972 (Folder 51: 12)
    Printed copy, reviews, and correspondence.
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1972; Typewritten notes and printed matter (Folder 51: 13-14)
  - "Two Views of Babi Yar,", 1972; Typescript (Folder 52: 1)
  - Letter to the editor, Encounter, 1972 May; Printed copy (Folder 52: 2)
  - "Some Reflections on the Origins and Nature of Totalitarianism," speech, conference, American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, Portland, Oregon, 1972 May 5 (Folder 52: 3)
    Typescript, printed copy, correspondence (1974), clipping, and French, German, Italian, and Japanese translations.
  - "Totalitarianism Revisited," speech, Stanford University, 1972 May 23; Typewritten notes and clippings (Folder 52: 4)
  - Review in Slavic Review of Vladimir Il'ich Lenin: Biograficheskaia Khronika, 1870-1924, Vol. I: 1870-1905 (Vladimir Il'ich Lenin: Biographical Chronicle, 1870-1924), 1972 September (Folder 52: 5)
  - Introduction to Julius Epstein, Operation Keelhaul: The Story of Forced Repatriation from 1944 to the Present, 1973 (Folder 52: 6)
    Mimeographed and printed copies, typescript, correspondence (1972-1973), and reviews.
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1973; Typewritten notes (Folder 52: 7-8)
  - Letter to the editor (with others), New York Times, 1973 January 16; Typescript (Folder 52: 9)
  - "Notes of a 'City' Boy," New York Times, 1973 April 20; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 52: 10)
  - "I Learn that Nobody Is Watching Me," Humanist, 1973 July-August (Folder 52: 11)
  - "Humanist Manifesto II" (with others), Humanist, 1973 September-October (Folder 52: 12)
    Mimeograph, printed copy, correspondence, and clippings.
  - "Some Mysteries of the Russo-American Detente," speech, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1973 October 24; Typescript and clipping (Folder 52: 13)
  - "Some Problems of the Russo-American Detente," speech, Central Slavic Conference, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater (1973 November 2)
    - General (Folder 52: 14)
      Printed copy, correspondence (1973-1975), and French translation.
    - Notes, Typewritten notes and printed matter (Folder 52: 15)
  - Review in Slavic Review of Lev Trotskii, The Young Lenin, 1973 December (Folder 52: 16)
    Printed copy and galley proofs.
  - "Old Bolshevism: Its Diversities," panel discussion, American Historical Association Meeting, San Francisco, 1973 December 29 (Folder 52: 17)
    Includes correspondence (1973-1974).
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1974; Typewritten notes and printed matter (Folder 53: 1-3)
  - The Story of Beseda: The Precursor of Kontinent, 1974 (Folder 53: 4)
  - "An Open Letter to President Nixon," Freedom First, 1974 January (Folder 53: 5)
    Typescript, mimeograph, printed copy, French translation (printed copy), and Russian translation (typescript and correspondence).
  - "Some Mysteries of the Detente," speech, Tulane University, New Orleans, 1974 March 26 (Folder 53: 6)
    Typescript and correspondence (1973-1974).
  - "Old Bolshevism," speech, International Conference, Banff, Alberta, 1974 September 5 (Folder 53: 7)
    Typewritten notes, correspondence (1973-1974), and conference program.
  - "Communist Ideology and Soviet Foreign Policy," lecture, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1974 October 20; Typewritten notes (Folder 53: 8)
  - Letter to the editor (with Ronald Hilton and Sidney Hook), New York Times?, 1974 October 23; Typescript (Folder 53: 9)
  - Introduction to Philip Jaffe, The Rise and Fall of American Communism, 1975; Typescript (Folder 53: 10)
  - Lectures, University of Colorado, Boulder, 1975; Typewritten notes (Folder 53: 11-12)
  - Letter to the editor, Daggas Nyheter (Stockholm), 1975 October 23; Typescript (Folder 54: 1)
  - Introduction to Robert W. Tolf, The Russian Rockefellers: The Saga of the Nobel Family and the Russian Oil Industry, 1976; Typescript (Folder 54: 2)
  - Review in New Lugano Review of Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn, Lenin in Zurich, 1976; Typescript and printed copy (Folder 54: 3)
  - "What Was Wrong with the American Revolution? A Study in Comparative Revolution," speech, American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies Convention, St. Louis, Missouri, 1976 October 8 (Folder 54: 4)
- Subject File, 1903-1977 (Boxes 54-151)
  Notes, correspondence, memoranda, clippings, and published and unpublished writings of others, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Abramovitch, Raphael (Folder 54: 5)
  - Acheson, Dean (Folder 54: 6)
  - Africa - Politics (Folder 54: 7-8)
  - Agriculture
    - General (Folder 54: 9)
    - Communist countries (Folder 54: 10)
    - Mexico (Folder 54: 11)
    - Russia
      - Clippings (Folder 54: 12)
      - Notes (Folder 54: 13)
      - Printed matter (Folder 54: 14-15)
      - Printed matter (Folder 55: 1-2)
      - Writings
        - Valkenier, Elizabeth Kridl, "The Land Question,", undated; Typescript (Folder 55: 3)
        - Volin, Lazar, "The Future of Soviet Agrarian Collectivism,", 1952; Mimeograph (Folder 55: 4)
        - Weeks, A. L., "Brief Discussion of the Contrasts between Agriculture in the U.S.A. and U.S.S.R.,", 1951; Mimeograph (Folder 55: 5)
    - U.S. (Folder 55: 6)
  - Akhmatova, Anna (Folder 55: 7)
  - Allilueva, Svetlana (Folder 55: 8)
  - Amalrik, Andrei
    - General (Folder 55: 9)
    - Speech, 1977; Mimeograph (Folder 55: 10)
  - Amerasia (Folder 55: 11)
  - American literature (Folder 55: 12)
  - Amnesty (Folder 55: 13)
  - Anarchism and anarchists
    - General (Folder 55: 14)
    - Russia (Folder 55: 15)
  - Anders, Wladyslaw (Folder 55: 16)
  - Anti-communist movements - U.S.
    - Notes (Folder 56: 1)
    - Printed matter (Folder 56: 2)
  - Antisemitism
    - Communist countries (Folder 56: 3)
    - Russia
      - Clippings (Folder 56: 4-5)
      - Notes (Folder 56: 6)
      - Printed matter (Folder 56: 7-8)
  - Arab countries (Folder 56: 9)
  - Area studies - Association for Asian Studies, Presidential Committee on Professional Needs and Development, "The Role and Funding of Asian Student Programs in the United States,", 1975; Mimeograph (Folder 56: 10-11)
  - Argentine Republic - Politics and government (Folder 57: 1)
  - Armaments
    - Clippings (Folder 57: 2)
    - Printed matter (Folder 57: 3-4)
  - Armand, Inessa (Folder 57: 5)
  - Aron, Raymond (Folder 57: 6)
  - Art
    - General
      - Clippings (Folder 57: 7)
      - Notes (Folder 57: 8)
      - Printed matter (Folder 57: 9)
    - Mexico (Folder 57: 10)
    - U.S.
      - Clippings (Folder 57: 11-12)
      - Printed matter (Folder 58: 1)
  - Asia - Politics (Folder 58: 2)
  - Atomic bomb (Folder 58: 3)
  - Atomic power (Folder 58: 4)
  - Austria - Politics and government (Folder 58: 5)
  - Babel, Isaak (Folder 58: 6)
  - Babiy Yar massacre (1941) (Folder 58: 7)
  - Bacciocco, Edward (Folder 58: 8)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica (Folder 58: 9)
  - Banks and banking (Folder 58: 10)
  - Beard, Charles A.
    - General (Folder 58: 11)
    - Correspondence - Vagts, Miriam, 1972 (Folder 58: 12)
  - Behaviorism (psychology) (Folder 58: 13-14)
  - Bell, Daniel (Folder 58: 15)
  - Berlin question (1945-) (Folder 58: 16)
  - Bernstein, Barton (Folder 59: 1)
  - Biological warfare (Folder 59: 2)
  - Birth control (Folder 59: 3)
  - Black market - Communist countries (Folder 59: 4)
  - Blok, Aleksandr - Alexandrova, Vera, "Alexander Blok,", undated; Typescript (Folder 59: 5)
  - Bolloten, Burnett (Folder 59: 6)
  - Bol'shaia Sovetskaia Entsiklopediia
    - General (Folder 59: 7)
    - Khinoy, Mark, "'National Bolshevism' in the New Soviet Encyclopedia,", undated; Typescript (Folder 59: 8)
  - Borodin, Mikhail
    - General (Folder 59: 9)
    - Jacobs, Dan N., "Borodin in China,", 1972; Typescript (Folder 59: 10)
  - Boudin family (Folder 59: 11)
  - Brecht, Bertolt (Folder 59: 12)
  - Brest-Litovsk, Treaty of (Russia) (1918 March 3) (Folder 59: 13)
  - Brezhnev, Leonid
    - Clippings (Folder 59: 14)
    - Newspaper issues (Folder 59: 15-16)
    - Notes (Folder 59: 17)
    - Printed matter (Folder 59: 18)
  - Bridges, Harry (Folder 60: 1)
  - Brodskii, Iosif (Folder 60: 2)
  - Brooklyn, New York (Folder 60: 3)
  - Browder, Earl
    - General (Folder 60: 4)
    - "Karl Marx and America,", undated; Mimeograph (Folder 60: 5)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew (Folder 60: 6)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr. (Folder 60: 7)
  - Budget
    - Russia (Folder 60: 8)
    - U.S. (Folder 60: 9)
  - Bukharin, Nikolai (Folder 60: 10-11)
  - Bukovskii, Vladimir (Folder 60: 12)
  - Bulgakov, Mikhail (Folder 60: 13)
  - Bureaucracy
    - General
      - General (Folder 60: 14)
      - Constas, Helen, "Bureaucratic Societies: Old and New,", 1957; Mimeograph (Folder 60: 15)
    - Russia
      - Clippings (Folder 60: 16)
      - Notes (Folder 60: 17)
      - Printed matter (Folder 60: 18-19)
    - U.S. (Folder 61: 1-2)
  - Calendar (Folder 61: 3)
  - California - Social conditions (Folder 61: 4)
  - Cambodia - Politics and government (Folder 61: 5)
  - Camus, Albert (Folder 61: 6)
  - Canada - Politics and government (Folder 61: 7)
  - Capital punishment - Russia (Folder 61: 8)
  - Capitalism (Folder 61: 9)
  - Carnegie, Andrew (Folder 61: 10)
  - Carr, E. H. (Folder 61: 11)
  - Censorship
    - General (Folder 61: 12)
    - Russia (Folder 61: 13-14)
  - Chambers, Whittaker
    - General (Folder 61: 15-16)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Folder 61: 17)
  - Chernov, Viktor (Folder 62: 1)
  - Chernyshevskii, Nikolai (Folder 62: 2)
  - Chertok, Benson T. (Folder 62: 3)
  - Chicherin, Georgii (Folder 62: 4)
  - Chile - Politics and government (Folder 62: 5-6)
  - China
    - General (Folder 62: 7-8)
    - Bibliography - Ma, John T., "Collecting Research Materials on the Subject of Post-1949 Mainland China,", 1970; Mimeograph (Folder 62: 9)
    - Economic conditions (Folder 62: 10)
    - Foreign relations (Folder 62: 11-12)
    - History
      - General (Folder 62: 13)
      - Civil War (1945-1949) (Folder 62: 14)
    - Politics and government (Folder 62: 15-16)
    - Social conditions (Folder 63: 1)
  - Churchill, Winston (Folder 63: 2)
  - Civil rights
    - General (Folder 63: 3)
    - Communist countries (Folder 63: 4-5)
    - India (Folder 63: 6)
    - U.S. (Folder 63: 7)
  - Clausewitz, Carl von
    - General (Folder 63: 8)
    - Paret, Peter, "The Political Ideas of Clausewitz,", 1962; Mimeograph (Folder 63: 9)
  - Cohen, Morris (Folder 63: 10)
  - College teachers - U.S. - Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr., and Seymour Martin Lipset, "The Contours of Academic Politics, 1972,", undated; Typescript (Folder 63: 11)
  - Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made Against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, New York, 1937
    - General (Folder 63: 12)
    - Correspondence, Schapiro, Meyer, 1937 (Folder 63: 13)
  - Committee on the Present Danger (Folder 63: 14)
  - Communication - U.S. (Folder 63: 15)
  - Communism
    - General
      - Clippings (Folder 63: 16)
      - Notes (Folder 63: 17)
      - Printed matter (Folder 63: 18-19)
      - Writings
        - Bittson, Anthony John, speech, 1973; Typescript (Folder 63: 20)